Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Intelligence Archive Secretary Gailane,
trace the record of the Yamato.
Ma'am.
This was observed in the Balan Star
System, 31.72 hebron miles away.
What incredible power !
That ship is dangerous.
Inform Maser's fleet, since they've been
ordered to invade the Zol system.
There's no need.
Sir ?
It won't shoot.
Even though the Yamato can shoot, it won't.
11th Planet of the Solar System
What a mess. Where's the Yamato...?
This is Yamamoto of the Cosmo Tigers.
Yamato, come in.
Yamato...!
Respond...
...please.
The wave motion shield is nearing its pressure limit !
One minute until wave motion shield failure.
We don't have time.
Keep the condition stable, and start up the sub-engine.
Send all energy to the main engine.
Hurry. The wave motion shield
won't hold much longer.
The Yamato will be crushed.
How is it, Analyzer ?
The block that can hold up the
cave by dispersing the load...
...identified.
Prepare to fire magnetron probes.
Fire !
Emit magnetron wave.
Losing the wave motion shield in five...
...four...
...three...
...two...
...one...
Probes are working normally.
It worked.
It's close, but holding.
Admiral Maser, there's a faint energy signature.
That Earth ship, the Yamato, appears to be intact.
Ignore it.
His Majesty has made his decision.
Fortunately, we're allowed
to use the Legionella Kanone.
Speed up the preparations.
Aye, sir.
This is the final look of a fake sun,
which sheds light on this remote planet.
So many of them...
Any word from the Yamato ?
Everyone's safe.
They can take off as soon as repairs are finished.
You'd better send this data to the Yamato...
...although knowing that won't change the situation.
Any problems ?
Not really.
An emotionless observation from a heartless person.
My translator may be malfunctioning.
Then why don't you take it off ?
Understanding languages without
some emotional connection is confusing.
Tsurumi.
Y...yes ?
Get the emergency rations from my
plane and take them to the Garmillan.
Even he gets hungry, right ?
You guys should eat, too.
O...okay.
Please forgive Commander Kato.
His son is ill, and his wife is...
That's not it.
Kato believes that the
Yamato will overcome this crisis.
That's why he snapped at me.
But the Yamato is different from before.
Everyone should be aware of it,
but no one openly talks about it.
Letting the Acting Captain shoulder all
the burden, is why we're in this situation.
You've been against this operation since the beginning, haven't you, Lieutenant ?
Even so, the fact is, the
Yamato did save a lot of lives.
If it can escape safely, Kodai's decision
will turn out to be the correct one.
He's stubborn, but not foolish.
Quite a lot, isn't it ?
According to Keyman, there were more
warp-outs after this data was sampled.
Analyzer.
Yes ?
The enemy fleet's formation seems abnormal.
Check the data so far, and predict their next move.
Roger.
So you're the Acting Captain, huh ?
Who are you ?
I'm Saito Hajime, commander of
the Space Cavalry 7th Regiment.
First, you have my utmost gratitude
from the bottom of my heart.
More than two hundred people were rescued.
Thank you so much for coming.
That being said,
I have a question for the Acting Captain.
Hey, what're you waiting for ?!
Why doesn't the Yamato fire the wave motion gun ?!
I have no answer for an outsider.
You're responsible for the people you've saved, aren't you ?
Hey, knock if off.
Many of the survivors think they can return to Earth because they're on the Yamato.
They believe so because it's the Yamato !
How're you going to escape this planet
without using the wave motion gun ?!
Tell me !
Keep it down.
It's an SOS...
...from the destroyed command center !
What ?
Aihara, let me hear it.
Remaining forces...if you can hear...command center.
...survivors below ground.
Commander Hijikata...badly injured...
The old man's alive ?
This is Kato from the fighter squadron.
The command center was assumed destroyed, but we
confirmed some survivors, including Commander Hijikata.
Commander Hijikata ?
Right now...
...the Space Cavalry's on its way to rescue them.
The radar is back online.
Enemy fleet confirmed, putting it on the main panel.
Why so many ?
Many enemy ships are still warping out.
It's exceeded 15,000 ships !
Cosmo Tiger squadron, stand by
and wait for my orders. That'll be all.
Roger.
Could that be...
Analysis complete.
The enemy Calakmul-class battleships
are forming a gigantic cylinder.
Expected time of completion is 10:20.
Expected total number of ships: approximately 2,500,000.
The cylinder is believed to be
some kind of accelerator, and...
...upon contact, the artificial sun in orbit will explode, eliminating everything within a 20,000 km radius.
Supernova explosion.
That shape could be...
Kodai, we have to hurry and escape.
Wait.
Analyzer, suppose the formation acts as a cannon, are there any planets in its line of fire ?
If such supernova energy is used by the expected size of the
enemy fleet, there's only one planet within its effective range.
Earth.
If anyone's alive, say something !
You sound rough, commander.
Old Man !
Please, promise me.
I promise.
Kodai, show your resolve.
Resolve ?
What do you mean by resolve, Captain Okita ?!
Kodai...
Kodai, let's use the wave motion gun.
We have no other way.
If that massive cannon is real,
the damage to Earth will be immeasurable.
He promised...
Captain Okita promised Starsia that
we'd never use the wave motion gun again.
Mr. Sanada, I...
I just want to do what I'm supposed to do, like keeping a promise or reaching out to those seeking help.
Don't you think that's how it's supposed to be ?
Kodai...
I'd be ashamed of being a resident of Earth if its people didn't have common sense.
If I could, I want to prove that
the people of Earth aren't like that.
That's why the Yamato...
Despite that, we must break our
promise and risk thousands of lives...
Acting Captain, Lieutenant Keyman's hailing us.
Kodai, it's dawn.
You might not be able to tell from down there, but the light of the artificial sun we installed is actually kind of beautiful.
Thank you, Lieutenant Keyman.
Good luck.
The ship will begin the wave motion gun firing sequence.
Start the sub engine.
Starting the sub engine.
Kodai, aim for the sun when it
reaches the center of those battleships.
Hang in there, Old Man.
We're almost there.
The Yamato's got a skilled doctor.
Commander, it's the Yamato !
What ?
Kodai, fire the wave motion gun !
You won't shoot our enemy even
though they're right in front of you, Kodai ?
No.
Kodai will shoot.
Admiral Maser, the Legionella Kanone
preparations are complete.
The sun will soon be
connected to the core point.
Good.
Prepare to fire the Legionella Kanone !
Open the channel to the wave motion gun.
Opening the channel.
Shut down all emergency valves.
Activate the forced injector.
Forced injector, activation confirmed.
Release the final safety.
Tachyon particle pressure rising in the chamber.
Energy charge, 120%.
Prepare to fire the wave motion gun.
The Yamato is going to shoot.
Take anti-shock and flash measures.
Target scope, open.
Optical cross gauge brightness 100.
Ten seconds till firing.
A number of cold spots appeared on the artificial sun. Energy transfer to the enemy fleet detected.
Three...
...two...
...one.
Fire !
What ? What's happening ?!
Some kind of interference wave caused
every ships' engine to malfunction.
Same principle as the special
depth-charge from before ?
Right.
A direct hit to the artificial sun's reactor generates interference waves because of the resonance.
They'll be immobilized for quite a while.
You saved us again.
The sun is beautiful at dawn.
That's all I told him.
This is Acting Captain Kodai Susumu
of the space battleship Yamato.
At present, our ship's firepower
can annihilate your entire fleet.
However, I do not wish any further hostilities.
I request that you quietly leave this space zone.
If you do, we will not attack you.
Although we come from different planets, we're
both human. I expect a wise decision from you.
Did he forgive...
Did he forgive our enemy ?
His way is not wrong, but that's only
if the enemy shares the same mentality.
This opponent is different from Garmillas.
We might end up paying a huge price.
Run.
He told us to run,
instead of killing or capturing us.
Why did the Yamato let us live ?
I...I just can't understand.
That's just...
That's love.
You fired it, and saved the
Earth without killing anyone.
Well done.
The truth is I fired the wave
motion gun by deceiving myself.
Kodai...
I know, I won't say that to anyone else.
Even if I'm deceiving myself, I must start from here.
Episode 7
Drastic Turn! Flash of the Wave Motion Gun
Kienai de aoi tsuki yo
Blue moon, please don't fade away
Kodai Susumu:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Aihara Yoshikazu:
Ohta Kenjiro:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Analyzer:
Saijo Miki:
Kato Saburo:
Shinohara Hiroki:
Ono Daisuke
Suzumura Kenichi
Otsuka Hochu
Akabane Kenji
Kokubun Masato
Chiba Yuki
Mugihito
Cho
Moriya Satomi
Hosoya Yoshimasa
Hirata Daisuke
Terashidasu kimi hitohira
It lights up my love just enough
Yamamoto Akira:
Tsurumi Jiro:
Saito Hajime:
Kurata Masaru:
Okita Juzo
Hijikata Ryu:
Keyman:
Starsia:
Zorder:
Sabera:
Gailane:
Balsey:
Lasera:
Cosmodart:
Maser:
Tanaka Rie
Komoto Keisuke
Tochi Hiroki
Yoshikai Kiyohito
Sugao Takayuki
Ishizuka Unsho
Kamiya Hiroshi
Inoue Kikuko
Tezuka Hideaki
Kaida Yuko
Shibata Hidekatsu
Nishimura Tomomichi
Harasawa Kouki
Kawai Toshiya
Kiyama Shigeo
Nani hitotsu kawaranai
Everything was routine
Monotone iro no hibi
Monotone days for so long
Unmei ga tsurete kita
Fate brought you to me
Kimi no me ni koi wo shita
I fell in love with your eyes
Chikaku ni kanjitai yo
I want to feel you close
Atatakai te ni furete
Touching your warm hands
Aa sugu ni kotoba ni dekitara
Wishing I could put this into words right away
Konnani ai shiteru
I love you so much
Kakurenai de koigokoro yo
Loving feelings, please don't hide
Kimi dake terashiteru yo
It sheds light only on you
Konya nara sou ieru
I can say that because tonight is different
Preview
I feel like Okita is still on this ship.
Identify yourself.
It's like a graveyard.
A civilian went off to the ruins ?
What's the meaning of this, Keyman ?
Kodai, where are you ?
My name is Zorder...
Episode 08
Trap On The Planet Stravase !